[engine starts, revs]
[Jerry] This is a 1985 Ferrari 308 GTB.
B for Berlinetta.
QV for Quattrovalvole.
Seven hundred and forty-eight made,
56 for the US.
Three in white.
It has a sharky nose.
It has a swoopy tail.
It has a mid-engine, three-liter,
240 horsepower,
four valve per cylinder V8.
[engine revving]
Chicks dig it. Dudes want it.
Ferraris are great cars.
They're fun to drive.
And they make people look.
And if you're a young guy
and things are breaking your way,
that's what you need.
It's a really nice car.
Which is why this is the perfect car
for my very special guest this week:
Mr. Trevor Noah.
Trevor Noah is a stand-up comedian
from South Africa,
who is the new host of The Daily Show
on Comedy Central.
He has a interesting,
complicated ethnic background
including many colors,
cultures, and languages.
None of that matters.
To me, he's just a funny guy.
[phone ringing]
-[Trevor] It's Trevor. Hello.
-[Jerry] Trevor Noah? Jerry Seinfeld.
-[Trevor] Hey, Jerry Seinfeld.
-[Jerry] You're a young guy,
you're hitting it big,
you need to show off a little.
Your job is to give the world
a little thrill.
Just drive, live it up, do your [bleep],
and the hell with it.
[Jerry chuckles]
I'm Jerry Seinfeld,
and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
Oh, wow. This is nice.
-[Trevor] I love cars.
-[Jerry] I didn't know that.
Oh, my God.
You're the perfect guest for the show.
Wow.
-Not bad.
-That's really nice.
We're like a detective team.
We've got that look to us.
Yeah, that's true.
This is definitely a '70s cop show.
-Yeah, look at us, you know?
-[Jerry] How about Noah and the Man?
[Jerry chuckles]
When I first came to New York,
I went gig-crazy. I didn't...
So, I was doing a show
at the Bleecker Street Theater,
and then after that, I would go
and I'd do six or seven shows.
I'd do an hour and half, and then I'd go
and do six or seven spots,
Thursday to Saturday.
Then Sundays, I'd fly to London.
And then I'd do a show
at a theater there for three days,
then fly back to New York
and do the same.
So I was doing this for a month.
Where did you get that
incredible work ethic?
From being poor.
[both laugh]
[Trevor] That's the weird thing about
trying to explain being a comedian.
Everything has a funny...
Like, everything, literally everything...
-Literally everything...
-Has a funny side.
Like, Nelson Mandela was extremely funny.
But nobody laughed at his jokes,
because it was Nelson Mandela.
They were releasing the Krugerrands
with his face on them.
And so at the press conference,
one of the BBC journalists said,
"Oh, Mr. Mandela, how does it feel
to go from being labeled
as a terrorist in your country
to now having your face
on the currency of that same country?"
So he looked at the journalist and said,
"That's how you know you've made it,
when you have your own money.
No more socializing with poor people."
And I think I heard you say that
your mother is half-Jewish. Is that true?
I think through her grandmother,
because we're mixed in the family
all the way down.
So she'll send me e-mails every day,
and then some of them will be half Hebrew,
and then I don't understand...
like, what she's saying.
[Jerry] E-mails every day...
that sounds Jewish.
The first time in my life I realized
how powerful comedy could be,
was we were in Johannesburg
during a parade/demonstration
and there were policemen on horses.
Everyone was petrified of policemen
on horses because they would beat you.
Everyone just knew this.
And as we're walking through the crowd,
my grandfather's walking with me,
the policeman comes up to us
and he shouts,
"Hey! Get out of the bloody way."
The previous weekend on the news,
the president had been
at a big horse-racing event
and the president had kissed
the winning horse.
It was on the front page,
him kissing the horse.
And my grandfather says,
[imitating grandfather] "Master,
I just need to ask you one question.
"Why is it that your president
can kiss a horse,
but he won't kiss my sister?"
He said, "I don't know why not."
And my grandfather looks at him and says,
"Because you haven't seen my sister."
The guy put his baton down,
he started laughing.
My grandfather laughed.
I'd never in my life seen a black man
and a white man laughing, like, together.
Talk-- I'd never ever seen this
in my life.
-[Trevor] Are we in Brooklyn?
-Yeah, we're in Brooklyn, in Dumbo,
which is a neighborhood in Brooklyn
that stands for
"Down Under Manhattan Bridge."
And then they added "Overpass,"
because nobody wants to live in "Dumb."
[indistinct conversation]
Every New Yorker I meet,
they want nothing to do with cars.
New Yorkers are like,
"I don't even have a driver's license."
If New York is the human body,
cars are germs.
That the antibodies
just seek to rid itself
through potholes, rust, and cost.
Get these items out of here.
-How you doing?
-Hey, how are you?
-Coffee?
-That's why we're here.
[Trevor] You really have to
come to South Africa.
Okay. Could we do something
there together?
How could I say no to that?
You have the humility of a colonizer,
that's what you have.
It's like you're holding the gun
and you're saying to me,
as the native on the land,
"Do you think we could share this land?"
-Like I have an option.
-Okay, you got me. I'm doing it.
And it's great, for the family as well.
They can go on safari.
They can, you know, it's like...
I know. My wife's dying to go.
I don't wanna go on safari.
So you see the elephants
and the lions in the wild. I just think,
"So these elephants I'm gonna see,
how similar are they to
the other elephants that I've seen?
They're exactly the same.
Yeah, they're exactly the same."
"But you're seeing them in the wild."
"Yeah, but it's the same elephant."
I'll tell you the thing I'm most
excited about on a safari.
The jeep.
That would be the thing
that would interest me the most.
[both laughing]
South Africa's similar to America.
Like, heckling is not allowed.
In the UK,
it's a very real part of comedy.
I went there.
I didn't even say a joke. Just,
"Hi, I'm Trevor Noah from South Africa."
And then some guy was like,
"Boo, get off the stage!"
And I panicked. I didn't know...
-Yeah.
-I didn't know what to do.
And then I kept quiet.
The audience went quiet.
I said, "Are you done?"
I said, "Forgive me. Where I'm from,
normally when white people come at you,
they come with dogs and tear gas.
Is that all you have?"
-Oh, my God. That's funny.
-And the whole crowd turned on him
because he was heckling the whole night.
So it was... And it was like, "Yeah!"
I would think being South African,
coming from that environment,
your emotional tone is to be tolerant.
Have to. Otherwise,
you'll be angry about everything.
You'll literally be angry
about everything.
Welcome, welcome to America.
[Trevor laughing]
-What's your routine when you wake up?
-I'm really more interested in yours.
My show's at 7:00,
so I wake up at 6:00 p.m.
6:00 p.m.?
Read the news, go into the shower,
get dressed, walk out of my apartment,
I walk into the venue,
walk into the backstage.
The guy will go, "You got
five minutes before you're on."
Then he gives me the mic, and I walk on.
That would be from 7:00 till 8:30.
-At night?
-Yes.
And then I'd leave through the back,
then I'll go have breakfast.
So I find a place, have breakfast,
and then after that I head to
the Comedy Cellar,
do a few spots, then I go to another club,
do a few spots.
Then come back to the Cellar,
then have dinner.
Then I do maybe one more spot.
Chat with comedians,
talk about anything until 3:00 a.m.
Go to the grocery store, do my shopping.
Head back home, and then I'll sleep
at, like, maybe 10:00, 11:00 a.m.
You know what? You're gonna do just fine.
[both chuckling]
You are a purebred.
Despite your mixed ethnic heritage,
your comedic heritage is very purebred.
Just take the highest paid
athletes in the world.
Let's say the top one guy on every team.
American football,
your football, whatever.
It's all the sports, okay?
What made you laugh about 'your football'?
That I'm trying to include you?
No, that you're excluding me.
-The Super Bowl.
-Yeah.
The final, the biggest sporting event
of football
had 100 million viewers watching.
A random match during the season,
not post-season,
not any final, no cup, nothing.
-Yeah.
-A match between Barcelona
and Real Madrid had 400 million viewers.
Clearly, that is the football.
By the rules of democracy,
and just numbers alone,
-that is the football.
-You're right.
-I like the World Cup.
-A lot of Americans like the World Cup.
They like the instantness
or the knockoutness of it, I think.
Yeah, and those look like the Germans.
You know? Those look like
the Mexicans. I get it.
And now, the Mexican team.
They come running out,
"Yeah, that is the Mexican team.
They look so Mexican."
If you just cut that piece out
and the person
who doesn't know Jerry Seinfeld,
doesn't know any part of the--
And you just snip that out, and you go,
"Yeah, that's what I like.
I like the people to look
like where they're from."
That's right.
Americans like cartoons. Crystal clear.
I like that.
I feel like you've taught me
so much already.
You don't need to know anything.
Everything you need to know,
you'll figure it out
when you need to know it.
Even if you miscalculate
and make the wrong decision,
-you needed to know that.
-Yes.
I always say that pain is knowledge
rushing in to fill a gap.
When you stub your toe
on the foot of the bed,
that was a gap in knowledge.
[both chuckling]
And the pain is a lot of information
really quick.
-That's what pain is.
-That's very funny.
-Are you on Twitter at all? Okay.
-Yeah.
I'm not of the generation
that got famous from their social media.
In fact, I use it
as a way to just talk to fans.
-In your underwear on your couch.
-[chuckles] Basically.
Doesn't it seem like we're striving
to take the entire life experience
and have it in our underwear?
You can socialize, do work,
get entertained, and get information
all in your underwear.
People are now able to protest
in their underwear.
And that almost defies
what protesting should be about.
The whole point of a protest
is to get out of bed,
put clothes on,
walk out into the cold, and say,
"I stand for this. I march for this."
But now, you don't really
have to have that conviction.
-No.
-'Cause you're on the couch
in your underwear.
Going, "You know?
I don't like it, either."
-In this ten-minute time frame.
-Exactly.
Punch in a few characters and you go,
"Yeah, yeah, I fought for the cause."
No, you didn't. It's the protesters
outside the Chinese thing.
-Of course.
-But there's no anti-protesters,
because people are like "Eh, I like China.
I like iPhones. So I'm not gonna..."
That's almost as bad as,
"Those look like Germans."
That's almost... Maybe worse.
-"I like iPhones, so I like China."
-How is that worse?
Because you've reduced this entire culture
that's billions of years old
and has some significant
human rights issues
to your phone that you like.
So anything else they do is okay with you.
-No. This is mine. You can't.
-Can I pay for it?
-Can I tell you why?
-I don't care why.
Wait a minute, I forgot my wallet.
Oh, that's perfect.
Please, let me. Please.
[indistinct conversation]
Look at this craziness.
They got a merry-go-round
encased in glass.
They need to fill this thing with water.
And then you ride the merry-go-round
with scuba gear.
That would be fun.
[indistinct conversation]
[Jerry] But look at what you get
here in Brooklyn. You get that view.
Don't you think London
has a similar thing?
-All those layers on top of each other?
-Yes.
You get one day a year like this
in London. One.
Yes. Just one. [chuckles]
And yet, there's a faint slither of hope,
because in every pharmacy,
you find them selling sunscreen.
It's "SPF hopeful."
[Jerry] This is Queens.
-Is Flushing in Queens?
-Yes.
Okay. I know that from The Nanny.
Right.
[Jerry] So, in South Africa,
comedy was illegal 21 years ago.
-Yes.
-What are you talking about?
It was illegal to stand up on a stage
and tell a joke?
Free speech was against the law,
so let's start there.
So, if you were to get up and
say anything that could be construed as
saying something about
what's happening around you,
and this was open to interpretation
by the government or the police,
you could then be locked up for inciting,
you know, the people.
They believe that what
you were doing was conspiring
-to overthrow the government.
-Wow.
You know, it's like watching
a National Geographic documentary
where they show the plants growing.
When they speed it up in time-lapse.
-Time-lapse.
-That's how we've had comedy.
[Jerry] So when did it
become a viable thing?
[Trevor] Oh, after 1994.
It now became, like,
it is no longer illegal to be black.
-So you can now do things.
-Wow.
So it's like, start by sitting
on the benches.
You know, start by riding in the bus.
Start by walking through the city,
at whatever time.
Then slowly, you go,
"What else can we do?"
You can sing,
you can do shows, you can act.
Can we tell jokes?
Yeah, you can tell jokes.
You'd have guys coming in
from the UK, from the US, going,
"I've been a comedian for 25 years."
"You're telling us you've done a thing
longer than we knew it existed."
[Jerry]
I've been doing comedy a long time.
Yeah, I started when I was 21.
-You're 61 years old?
-Mmm-hmm.
You've aged very well.
Well, I haven't worked my entire life.
Let's go back to your mother and father
getting married during apartheid.
You couldn't get married.
That's the point of apartheid, Jerry.
It is illegal for black and white people
to fraternize with one another.
Couldn't be in a relationship.
My mom would get arrested
when this would happen.
She'd have to pay a fine,
which was a very large amount
of money back then.
-Really?
-Yeah, and you'd pay the fine.
She'd go to jail for a weekend.
She'd pay the fine,
and then she'd do it again.
This is apartheid. Apartheid is literally
the perfection of racism.
You separate everybody
into the smallest groups possible.
-The Jews over here.
-Everybody.
Spanish over there.
We don't have Spanish people
in South Africa.
-Um, Russians?
-No Russians.
-Scandinavians?
-No Scandinavians.
Kiwis? You got kiwis?
Very few kiwis.
[Jerry] How did your mother and father
spend time together?
We lived in Soweto,
which was the township that all
black people basically lived in.
Right.
As a black person,
you could go into the city to work.
Have your work permit,
you go into the city, you work,
you have to leave
before the sun goes down.
If you're in town, the sun is down,
you get arrested.
That's how it works.
She would act like she was my dad's maid.
And then, that's how
we'd get into his apartment.
She had an outfit in a bag.
And not like sexy French maid.
-Literally, blue collar.
-Right.
You know, overalls, time to work.
What were you in this little play?
She would say that she was babysitting me
for a friend of hers
that was my skin color.
So you have white, you have black.
The problem is, every time
people break the rules, this comes out.
But in South Africa, this is not black.
They don't call me black.
They say you're colored. Black is black.
White is white. Colored is colored.
So then what happened was,
people would go,
"How do you have a colored baby?
Who helped you commit this crime?"
So then, my mom would go,
"No, this is not my baby."
-Oh, my God.
-"This is my colored friend's baby.
And then, I'm just looking after him."
-And this is late '80s?
-Yes.
-These people, these people.
-The whole system was absurd.
It doesn't make sense.
Racism, all of these things, when you look
at them, they don't make sense.
You know, Hitler... It doesn't make...
When you look now, you go,
"How did that craziness happen?
-It doesn't make sense."
-Right.
There's just a moment in time.
If you find the right balance
between desperation and fear...
-Right. That's correct.
-...you can make people believe anything.
[Jerry] Apartheid ended what year?
The date always throws me
because there was, like,
a soft release, then like a...
-Soft opening?
-Yeah. There was literally a...
They did that at
Marvel Adventureland, too.
They don't just open
all the rides before they...
-Start slowly.
-Yeah, they start slow.
You're a comic, you're knocking around.
Let's talk about when you became
the new host of The Daily Show.
First of all, do you know that
they're even thinking of you for this gig?
I was like, who's gonna get the job?
This is crazy.
Everyone at the show was like,
"Who's gonna get the job?"
Jon announces he's leaving,
it throws everybody off.
Because Jon does what no one seems to do.
And that's leave when the time is right.
Why is it time?
Why wouldn't he stay through the election,
which is the juiciest time for that show?
It's a political comedy show,
and a presidential election is coming up.
How is that good timing?
Please. Explain that.
He's got an eight-year-old
and a ten-year-old.
-It's the juiciest time in their lives.
-Come on.
This is the sick parenting culture
that we have in this country now.
-Tell me where you are when you find out?
-I'm in Dubai.
I'm literally driving in the middle
of the night and my phone rings.
And my manager says "How would you like
to be the host of The Daily Show?"
So, what did you do physically?
I get out the car and my legs...
I didn't have legs.
You know in those movies
where there's an explosion?
-Yeah.
-But instead of the sound of the explosion
you hear the silence.
The eardrums have all been pierced...
That's literally what happens.
And then, the worst thing is,
you're in Dubai,
which is one of the hardest places
in the world to find a drink,
and then you go, "Let's find a drink."
Let's find a drink in this Muslim,
Middle-Eastern country.
Even if we're getting arrested,
this is worth it, let's get that drink.
-Where is a drink?
-It's very closed-off, very...
It's not secretive,
but they keep the alcohol
away from the public, if that makes sense.
I see. So now we have liquid apartheid.
-You can't get away from it.
-You can't, Jerry.
-One fight at a time.
-Yeah.
Well, congratulations, my friend.
-Thank you very much.
-I'm very happy for you.
Thank you very much, Jerry.
[Jerry] Would you like to go
to the Mets game? Wanna go to see...
-[Trevor] Yeah, I'd love to.
-Fantastic, let's do that.
I feel like people need to know
that Jerry Seinfeld called Trevor Noah
long before The Daily Show said...
-Right.
-..."We want you as the host."
I had asked you to do the show
before any of this happened.
Yes, I hope you make that known
to everybody.
'Cause I feel like
you deserve that credit.
Because now I seem like an obvious choice.
Yeah.
And I feel like you're not
an obvious choice kind of guy.
Because I think, "This guy's cool.
I like his thing.
I wanna get to know him."